foreign
[Music]
Myanmar and extremely delighted to be
here just before coming to Myanmar I was
the CEO of bidb MetLife which is a joint
venture between brdb bank and MetLife
from the US in Vietnam and based out of
Hanoi we were very fast paced and a fast
growing life insurance company
and after joining manual life in Feb
2023 this is my first posting as the CEO
and looking forward to creating new
benchmarks and developing this industry
forward in Myanmar
I've spent almost all my professional
life in life insurance
and done variety of roles within life
insurance
uh and when I was looking at the
opportunity in Myanmar with Manu life uh
one of the first things that stands out
is the uh opportunity to make a
difference uh in this market in the
lives of uh 55 million plus customers uh
in a market which uh insurance has not
developed as much as it should have so
there is a lot of opportunity for
companies global companies like manolife
to really develop this industry further
and make a difference in the lives of
the customers that's really what excited
me because having again spent so much of
time in life insurance when you think of
a market which has a lot to catch up on
with very small penetration level of 0.1
percent uh I think it's best
fitting for a professional like me to
contribute in whatever way possible to
the development of the industry and to
really get this wonderful product of
life insurance which is so important for
families to millions of families in
Myanmar
I think that's a very important and a
relevant question and one of the biggest
challenges that we have in Myanmar is
the low awareness of life insurance
products life insurance as a concept
most families don't know about it and
they don't know how to talk about it to
the professionals uh so the biggest
challenge for us as an industry is to
really have that awareness uh go up from
the current levels and the only way the
awareness can go up is by having a
stronger distribution network uh more
financial advisors are needed in this
market uh who can sit across with
families sit across with people across
Myanmar and talk about the relevance of
life insurance and why the families need
to look at life insurance for their
confidence building as well as
protecting their families future and
unprecedented circumstances
so developing the distribution and
developing the advisor network is
extremely important for this industry to
develop further today as we look at it
we have about seven eight thousand uh
financial advisors in the market uh in a
population of 55 million people and if I
just uh compare this with uh the
previous Market where I was in Vietnam
uh with about 100 million people you
have about a million financial advisors
so you know just as a back of the
envelope calculation every 100 customers
have access to One financial advisor to
discuss about their financial needs as
well as life insurance so we have a long
way to go uh in Myanmar to really make
this as a household phenomena where
customers and families can get access to
One financial advisor and talk about
their needs uh the second bit uh is also
as this industry develops uh there is a
stronger need for uh making sure that
this industry develops in a responsible
manner particularly from a customer's
Viewpoint so as we develop uh products
as we develop more complex products as
we expand our distribution Network it
needs to be done in a very very
responsible Manner and I want to give an
example uh Insurance products uh start
with very simplistic endowment term life
purely protection products but they can
very quickly become complex for average
customers to understand and the role of
the financial advisor is therefore
extremely critical and the financial
advisor needs to spend time uh with the
insurance industry understanding the
product and really making sure that the
advisor stays with the customer through
the life of the policy and insurance
products tend to be very long term in
nature you know most of the products
that we sell are a minimum of 10 years
and what we really encourage our
financial advisors to do is to have a
10-year Horizon with the customer and
being with them through the entire life
cycle of the policy so
making sure we have a great distribution
strength uh and at the same time making
sure that the advisors have a long-term
vision of being with the customer over
the long term is extremely critical and
from a manual life perspective I'm very
happy as I start to manage this business
we have the best persistency where the
customers actually believe in the
product and they continue to pay their
renewal premium uh year on year giving
their confidence and vote of uh giving
the giving the vote of confidence to the
products that they have bought so that
is what I would like to see that the
industry does in the long term in
Myanmar
we have been in operation for uh a
little over three years and in this time
manual life has been able to attract
very good talent uh in Myanmar and while
attracting uh good talent in Myanmar
we've also been able to invest in that
talent for the long run and a large part
of that is also given by the fact that
banolife has a very very strong presence
across Asia so as we are building our
franchise in Myanmar we are able to tap
into some of the capabilities and you
know talents that we have in Asia
a lot of Myanmar people the employees
that we have in Myanmar have had the
chance to go and see manual life
operation and learn from those menu life
operations in Vietnam in Cambodia in
Hong Kong and that's really helped in uh
really
improving their capability in a very
very short span of time
and we believe that that process has to
be
ah continued we also make investments in
the learning of uh the people here for
example sponsoring them for courses of
Loma
uh also helping them uh you know learn
from their peers within the organization
through a mentor mentee program and we
continue to build our team of Highly
young enthusiastic people and I think
the first thing we look for when we are
hiring people is their enthusiasm and
motivation to be in life insurance and
also being very agile to learn from the
other operations uh outside of Myanmar
which which is I think one of the key
foundations of our people culture and
which will also help us in retaining the
people and developing the people for
serving a bigger business in the time to
come
I think the big part of this
communication is done through our
distribution Network and our constant
Endeavor is to be able to transmit our
values transmit our culture uh through
our distribution Network so today we
have almost uh close to 700 advisors we
have a fast growing network of Bank
Assurance through our 100 plus
Insurance Consultants that we have
deployed across the country
and they are as much a part of our
culture as much a part of our values as
all of us sitting in Young on are and my
experience is that if they understand
what you stand for the values that you
stand for and are able to participate in
that process equally passionately then
the job of you know at an organized
level the job becomes much simpler so
our constant source of Engagement our
constant source of motivation to them is
extremely critical when we have to make
sure that the customer is able to feel
the same level of confidence that we
want the customer to feel
Myanmar consumers families and the
Breadwinners are fairly young uh in
their age and I'm told that the median
age is about 29 and I see that in our
employee Force which is very young uh
most of them are in their early 30s just
starting their families
and uh
I would in terms of advice I would ask
them to ask themselves three questions
uh the number one question is a little
hard one but it's something that
everybody should ask if you are a
breadwinner in a family that today if I
am not there
will my family be as secured financially
as they are today while I am here so if
you remove yourself from the picture
what is it that your family would need
in terms of Financial Resources uh to
maintain the same standard of living
that they currently have of course the
emotional part of it cannot be addressed
but financially it is our responsibility
as Breadwinners to really ask that
question from ourselves what would it
take for my family to maintain the same
standard of living if I was not there
because of some reason
number two is also something that
everybody hopes that if
I'm there 10 years 20 years down
what is it that my money can do to help
me lead a better or a more confident
life so if I if I am still living will I
have enough or more resources than what
I would need for my child for my wife
for my my own self Etc so how is it that
you can enhance your money over a longer
period of time so long term savings is
the second bid and the third bit which
is an emerging bit now is given certain
health conditions which can happen to
anyone in the family and you would want
nothing but the best in terms of
treatment for the family
would the family be able to afford if
somebody was to let's say get a good
treatment for maybe a some sort of a
cancer in Thailand or in Singapore or
anywhere else so it would put a drain on
your resources so therefore you should
be prepared to fund those through some
means Without Really bringing down your
lifestyle or without dipping into your
own savings which you have saved for
your child's education or your
retirement so number one make sure that
you prepare for a bad eventuality if you
are not there how would your family
maintain uh the same level of living
number two if you do live then how can
you multiply your resources how can you
make sure that you have more savings
than you what you would need and number
three if there was a eventuality in
terms of health
how would you
protect it in terms of Financial
Resources so buying a life insurance for
protection buying a life insurance for
long-term savings and buying a life
insurance for health is something that
everybody should think as a as a
responsibility towards their families
so while manner life is a global
organization uh when it comes into a
market like Myanmar uh we do understand
that we have to adapt to the local
culture we also have to identify uh
stakeholders as well as communities
where we can make a positive difference
and we continue to do that even though
we are fairly new in Myanmar we have
already started to look at you know
potential Partnerships with the
communities where we would like to make
a difference and I would share two
examples to illustrate that number one
is our partnership with Down Syndrome
Association
where we very proudly
participate and work with the foundation
with the association as well as the
children of the association our
employees give up a lot of their time to
spend with the children I myself have
done that over the last few months that
I've been there uh and also on the
environment side uh we see a lot of
opportunities where we can partner and
make a positive difference
um so sustainability and environment is
uh something again very close to uh
manual lives values uh recently I was
at the katong beach where we planted uh
corals uh we are trying to propagate the
coral Plantation
in an area which has been disturbed
because of global warming Etc
so these are small efforts and
eventually will lead to some results but
at the same time we are very proud to be
continuing to do that in the next few
years and you will hear more as we do
that more in Myanmar in the coming time